<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rahul Setrakian</title>
    <link>https://rahulsetrakian.org/</link>
    <description>Hi, my name is Rahul Setrakian. I&#39;m a self-taught programmer with a passion for cybersecurity and innovation. Join me on this exciting journey!</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 16:32:02 &#43;0530</pubDate>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <atom:link href="https://rahulsetrakian.org/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Importance of Two-Factor Authentication in Online Security</title>
      <link>https://rahulsetrakian.org/blog/importance-factor-authentication-online-security/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://rahulsetrakian.org/blog/importance-factor-authentication-online-security/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 11:14:52 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      <description>BlogTwo-Factor Authentication, Cybersecurity, Authentication MethodsImportance of Two-Factor Authentication in Online Security With a thorough understanding of 2FA, you can better safeguard your digital presence and mitigate the risks associated with unauthorized access &amp;amp; data breaches. Reading TimeMins
ViewViews
Publish DateSeptember 17, 20231. Introduction to Two-Factor Authentication In today&amp;rsquo;s digital landscape, the security of our online accounts and personal information is of paramount importance. With the increasing prevalence of cyber threats and data breaches, it has become essential to implement robust security measures to protect ourselves and our sensitive data.</description>
      <enclosure length="38" type="image/jpeg" url="https://rahulsetrakian.org/assets/img/shutterstock_641960737.jpg"/>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cryptojacking: What It Is and How to Prevent It</title>
      <link>https://rahulsetrakian.org/blog/cryptojacking-prevent/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://rahulsetrakian.org/blog/cryptojacking-prevent/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 11:48:36 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      <description>BlogCryptojacking, Cryptocurrency Security, MalwareCryptojacking: What It Is and How to Prevent It In this article, you can learn to enhance the security of your cryptocurrency wallet and mitigate the risk of falling victim to cryptojacking attacks. Reading TimeMins
ViewViews
Publish DateSeptember 12, 20231. Introduction to cryptocurrency wallets and cryptojacking attacks Cryptocurrency wallets have become an essential tool for securely storing and managing digital assets.</description>
      <enclosure length="43" type="image/jpeg" url="https://rahulsetrakian.org/assets/img/Bitcoin-Clipboard-Hijacker.webp"/>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differences Between Front-End &amp; Back-End Development</title>
      <link>https://rahulsetrakian.org/blog/exploring-differences-front-development/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://rahulsetrakian.org/blog/exploring-differences-front-development/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 12:21:16 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      <description>BlogFront-End Development, Back-End Development, Web Development RolesDifferences Between Front-End &amp;amp; Back-End Development Front-end and back-end development are two essential components that collectively power the web applications we interact with every day. Reading TimeMins
ViewViews
Publish DateSeptember 5, 20231. Introduction to Front-End and Back-End Development Front-end and back-end development are two essential components that collectively power the web applications we interact with every day. While both contribute to the seamless functioning of websites and web applications, they involve distinct sets of skills, technologies, and responsibilities.</description>
      <enclosure length="43" type="image/jpeg" url="https://rahulsetrakian.org/assets/img/Front-end-vs-Back-end-copy.webp"/>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harry Potter – CTF Walkthrough</title>
      <link>https://rahulsetrakian.org/blog/harry-potter-ctf-walkthrough/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://rahulsetrakian.org/blog/harry-potter-ctf-walkthrough/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 13:01:24 &#43;0530</pubDate>
      <description>BlogTryHackMe, Write-Up, Capture The FlagHarry Potter – CTF Walkthrough Harry Potter CTF walkthrough, This is the official write-up, and I will guide you through the whole process step by step. Reading TimeMins
ViewViews
Publish DateJuly 25, 2023CTF Walkthrough Hello there, welcome to the official write-up of Harry Potter – CTF. I created this room for fun. I made this room in a few hours.</description>
      <enclosure length="15" type="image/jpeg" url="https://rahulsetrakian.org/post/harry.jpg"/>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India&#39;s Ban on Encrypted Messaging Apps: A Disturbing Assault on Privacy and Free Speech</title>
      <link>https://rahulsetrakian.org/blog/indias-ban-on-encrypted-messaging-apps-a-disturbing-assault-on-privacy-and-free-speech/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://rahulsetrakian.org/blog/indias-ban-on-encrypted-messaging-apps-a-disturbing-assault-on-privacy-and-free-speech/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 08:32:49 &#43;0530</pubDate>
      <description>BlogPrivacy, Free Speech, EncryptionIndia&amp;#39;s Ban on Encrypted Messaging Apps: A Disturbing Assault on Privacy and Free Speech India&amp;#39;s ban on encrypted messaging apps undermines privacy and free speech, setting a dangerous precedent for democracy and citizens&amp;#39; rights. Reading TimeMins
ViewViews
Publish DateJune 27, 2023India&amp;rsquo;s Ban on Encrypted Messaging Apps “Privacy is not a privilege, it is a fundamental right.” - Edward Snowden
In a shocking move, India, once hailed as the world&amp;rsquo;s largest democracy, has taken a giant leap towards eroding privacy and stifling free speech by banning encrypted messaging apps on a massive scale.</description>
      <enclosure length="16" type="image/jpeg" url="https://rahulsetrakian.org/post/post-2.jpg"/>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
